<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Convolutional Neural Networks on Manuel Martinez</title>
    <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/categories/convolutional-neural-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Convolutional Neural Networks on Manuel Martinez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manmartgarc.github.io/categories/convolutional-neural-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional Neural Networks: Week 3 | Detection Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/cnns/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/cnns/week3/</guid>
      <description>This is the third week of the fourth course of DeepLarning.AI&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning Specialization offered on Coursera. The week focuses on object detection and localization, important applications of computer vision where CNNs serve as a building block to more specialized applications.
This week&amp;rsquo;s topics are:
Object Localization Landmark Detection Object Detection Sliding Windows Detection Convolutional Implementation of Sliding Windows Turning fully connected layers into convolutional layers Implementing sliding windows convolutionally Bounding Box Predictions Intersection Over Union Non-max Suppression Anchor Boxes Semantic Segmentation Transpose Convolutions U-Net Architecture Summary Object LocalizationLink to headingObject localization is, intuitively, not just detecting an object in an image, but also being able to describe its position in the image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional Neural Networks: Week 2 | Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/cnns/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/cnns/week2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second week of the fourth course of DeepLarning.AI&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning Specialization offered on Coursera. This week is largely a literature review, going over different architectures and approaches that have made large contributions to the field.
This week&amp;rsquo;s topics are:
Case Studies Classic Networks LeNet5 AlexNet VGG16 ResNets Why do ResNets Work? Networks in Networks | 1x1 Convolutions Inception Network Inception Network Architecture MobileNet Depth-wise Convolution Point-wise Convolution MobileNet Architecture Practical Advice for Using ConvNets Transfer Learning Data Augmentation Summary Case StudiesLink to headingWe should obviously keep up with the computer vision literature if we are interested in implementing new ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convolutional Neural Networks: Week 1 | Foundations of CNNs</title>
      <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/cnns/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/cnns/week1/</guid>
      <description>This is the first week of the fourth course of DeepLarning.AI&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning Specialization offered on Coursera. This course introduces convolutional neural networks, an extremely popular architecture in the field of computer vision.
This week&amp;rsquo;s topics are:
Computer Vision Convolution Convolution in continuous land Convolution in discrete land Back to Edge Detection Learning the Filters Padding Strided Convolutions Convolutions Over Volume One Layer of a CNN Defining the Notation and Dimensions Simple CNN Example Pooling Layers Full CNN Example Why Convolutions?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
