<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Manuel Martinez</title>
    <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Manuel Martinez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neural Networks and Deep Learning: Week 1</title>
      <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/nn-dl/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/coursera/deep-learning-specialization/nn-dl/week1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Deep LearningLink to headingThis is the first course in the Coursera&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning Specialization. I will try to summarize the major topics presented in each of the weeks in each course in a series of posts. The purpose of this is to both deepen my own understanding by explaining, but also for people who have not taken the specialization. Hopefully these posts will inspire you to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSCode and Tiny Instances over Remote SSH</title>
      <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/tech-support/vscode-ec2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/tech-support/vscode-ec2/</guid>
      <description>VSCode is very popularLink to headingA lot of people like VSCode, 74% of respondents in StackOverflow&amp;rsquo;s 2022 Developer Survey said that VSCode is the IDE that they&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past year and also plan to keep using it. Why is VSCode liked so, and what do people like about it is not the focus of the post; but for sure it has to do with its extendable functionality, much of which comes from extensions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Mistakes and Information frictions in College Admissions</title>
      <link>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manmartgarc.github.io/posts/mistakes/</guid>
      <description>This is a working paper with Anaïs Fabre, Tomas Larroucau, Christopher Neilson and Ignacio Rios. The paper explores how information and beliefs have an effect on outcomes within the tertiary education market in Chile, which is a centralized college admissions system. The paper includes two waves of surveys done in 2019 and 2020 and an RCT done in 2021 with both government and NGOs. The abstract is below, and you can find the latest version of the working paper here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
